Last week on the show we said August 4th
was the day that SpaceX [music] had to
prove themselves. The first earnings
report every analyst on Wall Street
basically was [music] bearish. They said
that Elon Musk could not pull this off
that this thing is a money vacuum. Turns
out the opposite was the case. SpaceX
absolutely smashed [music] it. The
revenue is up to $7.81 billion which is
92% [music] year-on-year which is crazy
for the size that they're at and
Starlink numbers doubled to 12 million
subscribers. That being said, the stock
is still down this morning. People are
worried about the major unlocks that are
happening tomorrow where $100 billion
worth of SpaceX stocks goes live. But
Josh and I are here to tell you why that
may not be the case and why the market
could be wrong.
>> Yeah, well I understand why people are
bearish. Like he was on the earnings
call yesterday which I sat in and
listened to and he's claiming he's like,
"All right, we're going to build robots
with mesh drivers on the moon and we're
going to 1000x our economy on Earth
because of it." And it sounds
ridiculous. And I was looking through
the numbers and as I was reading this I
was like slowly starting to inform
myself on what large companies look like
and E just I want to start with a
question to you actually. Do you know
what company had the most annual revenue
ever? Like what what company is making
the most money every year? This was
really surprising to me.
>> Like currently? Like right now?
>> Yeah. Like like total revenue per year.
Like who's making the most?
>> I would have to say it is either like an
Nvidia or an Amazon.
>> It's not even a tech company. It's it's
Walmart.
>> Walmart?
>> Walmart popped out at $680 billion of
revenue which seems outrageous and I
mean it gets into the pricing thing
where like Walmart's not the biggest
company in the world. Why is that? Well,
because their profit margins are low,
their multiples are lower. But SpaceX
and Elon went on this conference call
and he said, "Hey, we actually ran the
numbers and instead of 2031 by the year
2030 they expect to have a trillion
dollars in revenue. That is 40% or 32%
more than the largest company on Earth
today. I think we kind of have to unpack
what that looks like because I mean that
is a tremendous amount of value given
the fact that they actually just
reported a net loss of half a billion
dollars, which is an improvement but
still a net loss. You can kind of break
down the company's earnings report into
these three pillars. First, it is
connectivity, which is like Starlink and
all of their satellite situations. Then
they have AI, which was up 250%
year-over-year. And then they had space,
which was up 30% year-over-year. And I
mean the important thing that you noted
is that 32% growth year-over-year is
uh sorry, 92% growth is huge because for
companies with $30 billion of annualized
revenue, typical growth is like 5 to
10%. So clearly they're doing something
right.
>> I was keeping an eye on his social media
yesterday and one of the things that he
said is we are on track for a $100
billion
ARR by the end of this year.
>> This year?
>> 2026. Now, the only other company that
I've heard that projection being made
for is Anthropic. Now, when I look at
SpaceX look at Anthropic, I'm saying,
"Okay, well, they they may be competing
in the same sort of field, but I don't
think SpaceX is quite caught up on the
AI side, but that's what most people
miss. SpaceX isn't just an AI company,
they are a computation company. They
have the largest arsenal, largest GPU
footprint of Nvidia GPUs, might I add.
And he signed a major partnership with
Jensen, which we'll get to in a second,
but he's the only person that's
launching these things into orbital
space. You know, he has the largest data
center cluster on Earth, and he's also
doing the Starlink connectivity thing.
So all of these are different revenue
drivers. And what I like about this
report is he's proved a lot of the bears
wrong simply by the numbers. Like let's
actually like walk through some of these
numbers, right? So revenue, the estimate
was $6.93 billion.
He smashed it by earning almost a
billion dollars more than that, right?
And then when you look at earnings per
share, people were like, "Okay, they're
going to be like at a net loss of 26
cents per share." Nope, came in at 0.09.
Is it profitable yet? No, but it is
still much better than people expected.
Then the net income, as you mentioned
earlier, people were expecting a $2
billion loss. He shaved that down by 3x
to half a billion dollars. Now, again,
is this the best earnings report that
they could have come up with? Probably
not, but this these things take time for
a capex-heavy company such as SpaceX.
I'm really impressed with what they've
been able to pull off, and I think like
it just kind of like shows that Elon has
pretty crazy statements. I remember when
he pitched like the Starlink
robot GPUs in space vision about what
was this like 12 months ago for the the
GPUs in space, and everyone thought he
was absolutely insane, but every step he
takes, every earnings report he takes,
we're starting to see a different
picture start to form. And I'm not
saying he's there yet. I'm I'm just want
to be very clear. Like I don't think
we're anywhere near that, but this is a
step in the right direction, and I think
that, you know, after listening to the
the call yesterday and after seeing a
lot of the reporting, I think he might
be there. But, of course, something that
people are worried about is the unlock
that is happening tomorrow. And I don't
know if you have any thoughts on this,
Josh, but like $100 billion is flooding
the market.
>> Yeah, well, I mean, there's going to
need to be a lot of shares that are
moving cuz SpaceX is also among the most
shorted companies in the marketplace
right now. So, there's there's a lot of
short positions on it. There's a lot of
people that are bearish. There is a lot
of unlocks happening. Whether or not
those unlocks become bullish or bearish
is TBD, but my expectation is like I I
don't really care. Like as an investor
over a long period of time, like okay,
maybe it sells off for the next couple
days, maybe it sells off for the next
week, maybe the next month. But, I mean,
the numbers are pretty amazing. And you
could see why people are getting scared.
You mentioned the capex. Capex was 39%
higher than what people thought. It came
in at just under 18 and 1/2 billion
dollars, which NASA's like annual budget
is 25 billion, so they spent almost the
entirety of NASA's budget in a single
quarter. That also means that they spent
$2.35 for every dollar that they made in
revenue. And you have to ask the
question like, where is that going? Why
are they spending so much? Because this
sounds like lunacy. If it's like if you
have imagine a restaurant, you're
investing in a restaurant and they come
and they spend $23,000 a night even
though they're only making $10,000 a
night. You say, "What on earth is going
on here? This makes no sense." But then
they tell you, "Wait a second, we're
we're building out new restaurants.
We're building a higher profit margin
menu items." And that's kind of what
SpaceX is doing
on the data center front. So, one of the
smaller things that I think a lot of
people overlooked is the fact that they
already have a backlog of about $50
billion
of revenue that's already signed. Like,
no one even has to pick up the phone and
they're collecting $50 billion just
because of their ability to build these
data centers. And this is where we kind
of talk about data centers for a second,
which is their like very much an unfair
advantage. On the earnings call I was
listening to their CFO, Bret Johnson, I
think his name is. He said that like all
capex isn't the same. Some capex is much
more lucrative than others. And in the
case of SpaceX, it's about as lucrative
as we've heard. A lot of companies,
let's say you invest in an apartment
building and you build this huge piece
of real estate, it takes about 15 to 20
years to pay itself back. SpaceX's data
centers pay themselves back in a single
calendar year. So, in terms of return on
invested capital, it's like this
unbelievable arbitrage opportunity where
it feels like they they have this unfair
advantage being that they're the only
ones that could build these data centers
quickly and efficiently and then go off
and sell these huge unbelievably large
contracts to companies that can't do the
same. And my favorite quote from the
earnings call, my favorite one by far is
what Elon was asked about terrestrial
data centers. This is after he concluded
about the space data centers, which
we'll get to in a minute.
But the terrestrial data centers, he's
like, "This is like the New York Yankees
playing in a little league." It feels
like they're just night and day
difference in terms of their ability to
execute on these things. And their
return on the invested capital is huge.
You can't buy a Blackwell GPU, period.
So, that's why people are paying
premiums. In fact, if you are currently
signed to a Blackwell contract, you are
trying to extend the length of that as
much as you can because if it renews,
it's going to renew at double the cost
because the cost of this compute is so
expensive. The only people that are able
to build it at scale as quick as they do
is SpaceX. And I mean return on invested
capital on an investment this large
being 12 months, you could very quickly
see why their revenue models are guiding
towards something closer to a trillion
than where we currently are over the
next 4 years or so. It's It's
unbelievable.
>> Just to focus on the the GPU point for a
second, right? Like I think a lot of
people are worried The the doomers for
the AI bubble say that the bubble is
primarily formed in GPU CapEx
specifically. So, all these trillions of
dollars that is being committed and
spent on Nvidia GPUs, AMD GPUs, whatever
that might be is where the bubble is
inflating because these machines will
eventually, you know, depreciate. They
won't actually be in demand once the
cost of tokens go down, etc. etc. etc.
What we've seen from every single
quarterly earnings report from all of
the major hyperscalers, which are the
ones that are investing the most,
including or aside to SpaceX. So, if you
look at Amazon, Google, they're all
reporting record revenue numbers. In
fact, all their cloud service provider
platforms, like Azure, like Google
Cloud, like AWS,
not only is their revenue increasing by
like I think it's like 40 to 45%
compounded every single quarter, by the
way. That's every 3 months.
>> [laughter]
>> Just I don't know
>> people understand how absolutely insane
that is. Not only is it compounding
their revenue specifically, but their
margins are expanding even more. So,
they're making more money on the money
that they're earning, which is just like
an insanely good business. So, Elon saw
this and was like, well, I have more
GPUs than any of you, and I'm building
these data centers faster than any of
you. It would make sense for us to
become like a new cloud service, and
that's why he's selling upwards of $50
of AI compute to the likes of Anthropic,
Google, and whoever that might be going
forward. So, he's seen that it's a
hugely profitable business. And what I
love about one of the major
announcements that he made yesterday is
he came out and said, "We are going to
be exclusive to Jensen. We're going to
be exclusive to Nvidia." And verbatim,
he quotes, "Going forward, we've decided
to build exclusively on Nvidia because
we think that the Vera Rubin
architecture is the best architecture.
We think it's the best AI computer, and
so we're going to be exclusive to
Nvidia." Now, the craziest part about
this is what he committed to buying. He
is basically going to double his
existing Well, SpaceX's existing GPU
fleet by the end of next year. I cannot
emphasize enough how crazy of an attempt
that's going to be. That is going to be
in Nvidia's pocket. Let's say he pulls
this off, right? Let's say he he gets to
the 10 gigawatts cumulative worth of
GPUs by the end of next year. That is
$200 billion from SpaceX alone in
Nvidia's pocket by the end of next year.
Now, let's be realistic. Let's say like,
you know, he's at two two and a half
gigawatts. He'll get to three by the end
of this year. Let's say he gets to like
six gigawatts by the end of next year.
That is an extra $100 billion
in Nvidia's pocket. He's going to be his
number one customer, and he's taking a
massive commitment with Jensen. And this
is interesting because a few days
earlier, Anthropic signed this major
deal with AMD. They're signing major
deals with other cloud service
providers. Elon has basically said,
"Jensen, if you can guarantee me the
allocation, we will take the compute,
and that is my commitment to you going
forward, even when we launch them into
space." Right? So, I'm just massively
bullish on the cloud business, on the
compute business that he's built. I
think even if everything falls to the
wayside, Elon still has a very
profitable business, and people are
discounting that massively right now.
This deal is pretty interesting to me,
too. It's because we're seeing a lot of
these accelerator chips. We're seeing
like the training chips and the the TPU
chips from Google. And everyone's kind
of focused Even OpenAI is building their
own vertically integrated chipset. And
it's interesting to see SpaceX going the
other direction. They're saying, "Well,
we are going to build our own chips to
some extent, but we're also going to
work with Nvidia to use their new
architecture. And we've talked a lot
about how this new Blackwell era of
models is unbelievable. The Vera Rubin
era of models is going to probably be
like remarkable. And SpaceX will be
using that exclusively, which is very
bullish because then I assume it works
both ways, right? It's like Nvidia gets
this amazing showcase to share with the
world. Like, "Hey, look what our GPUs
can do. Look how fast they could be
deployed."
And the SpaceX team gets a much more
tighter feedback loop with the team when
it comes to development of the software
architecture, the hardware architecture.
And I assume that's going to turn into
like a pretty nice partnership from both
of these companies. I mean, both
founders love each other. Both are at
the top of their game. It's It's very
exciting to see this happen. And the
tentative plan he does, you were talking
about how many gigawatts they were
planning to deploy. On the conference
call, Elon initially said 10 by the end
of 2027. And then when people pressed
him by the end of the decade, around
2030, he is guiding towards roughly 20
gigawatts of power with a floor of 15
gigawatts. So, he's like, "All right.
Well, even if everything goes wrong, we
can at least get to 15 gigawatts." For
reference, we've talked about this a
lot, but like a singular gigawatt of
power is equivalent to roughly 800,000
homes. It's like cities worth of power.
And they're planning to do 15 of these
in the next 4 years. Like, that's That's
really fast. The other thing is, I mean,
Jensen has his own kind of rule of thumb
when it comes to deploying gigawatts of
energy. He says you can guide for around
40 to 50 billion dollars of annual
revenue per gigawatt. So, if SpaceX does
get 15 gigawatts of solar capacity by
the end of the decade, that alone is
worth 600 to 750 billion dollars of
revenue. And that doesn't include the
other pillars of this company, which are
space and connectivity. So, there is
this like unbelievable bull case even if
you disregard all of the other pillars
of the business. But in addition to
this, there are these pillars like AI
data centers in space, which again
they're being built with Jensen Huang
and Nvidia. And the idea, I found this
really interesting for their AI one
satellites, is they're basically going
to build the same thing on Earth as they
are going to be in space. The only
difference is they're going to put some
solar panels on this bad boy and send it
off into space. So, this vertical
integration of the hardware stack as it
relates to terrestrial, as it relates to
space, is just remarkable. And then if
they actually figure out how to get
payload into space at scale, oh my god.
Like you start to put the numbers
together, you're like, wait a second.
They actually could do this thing. And
like what is the stock going to be
trading at if they get terrestrial data
centers 15 gigawatts online in four
years, and also they start putting mass
into space at scale, like isn't it going
to be a pretty huge opportunity? The
biggest critique that I hear from a lot
of you listeners that watch this show is
that this vision, this plan is just too
insane to pull off. And honestly, like I
agree with you, but you also have to
look at the evidence of things that can
actually make the company money that
will help fuel Elon and SpaceX getting
to some of the more crazier visions,
right? And one of the main ones is this
compute revenue business that he's kind
of showcasing and saying, "Hey, this
thing makes money and we're going to be
the biggest betters on this, right?
We're going to be able to pull this
off." And if he's able to secure that
capacity with the likes of Jensen and
Nvidia, and Jensen loves Elon Musk so
much, he will be able to pull this off.
Now, just to kind of translate kind of
like what this compute means for Elon,
it's not just a way to kind of like earn
money by selling compute to competitors.
He's also very much using this to train
some of the best AI models in the world.
And of course, like you might listen to
that and like laugh, but if you kind of
like span out the timeline over the next
kind of 6 to 12 months, the only thing
that is consistent across every single
model, different model architecture,
whatever, like, you know, different
weights that you use, it is compute. You
need more compute to pre-train, you need
so much more compute to post-train, and
then you need compute to serve this to
people at like perfect speeds and
quality of service. You just need more
compute. And in order to do that,
there's two things you need to look at.
You need enough capital to buy the GPUs,
but you also need enough capital to buy
the best GPUs. To walk hash had an
amazing blog post. I don't know if you
read it, Josh. He basically said the
better the GPUs get, the better AI
models these GPUs can unlock. Which
means that Nvidia will basically sell
these GPUs to the highest bidder. Who
are the highest bidders going to be?
Like I like this example. There's two
companies, okay? Company A wants to use
100,000 GPUs to cut down a bunch of,
let's say, administrative workload at
that company by 30%. That is a really
meaningful impact, right? And they'll
save a ton of money and they'll be able
to generate millions of dollars. Great.
But there's a problem. Company B wants
those same GPUs to train and cure
cancer, right? Over a month. And they
know that if they can do a one training
run with their data, they'll be able to
cure cancer. Who's going to bid more?
It's going to be company B. So, these
GPUs are like very, very scarce. And at
the end of the day, the people that have
the most capital will buy these GPUs and
train the best models. They'll train the
best features, products, services,
whatever that might be. And Elon is at
the front of all of this. It's not even
Anthropic or OpenAI. He has secured the
most allocation. He has the largest
arsenal of GPUs right now. So, it goes
to say that he could potentially create
the best AI model, Grok 4.6, Grok 4.7,
and Grok 5 is going to be coming up by
the end of this year. And he said it's
going to be trained on all of SpaceX's
data, which would technically make it
like the best engineering AI model. So,
there's a lot of these things that are
kind of like in the oven. They're
cooking. And we don't quite see them
right yet, but it's good to be just
generally aware of. I I don't know. I'm
just very optimistic about like where
this could be in 6 to 12 months.
>> Yeah, there's a lot of really
high-quality shots on goal that they're
taking. Where even if one completely and
catastrophically fails, there's still
many others that are doing well. And
it's funny hearing a space company talk
about terrestrial data centers. They're
talking about like they're actively
trying to send these things into space
that are actually trying to blow
themselves apart. And it's just like,
how easy is it that you could just drop
these things on Earth and it's easy and
the atmosphere is easy to handle and and
it just seems like going back to the
baseball analogy, it's like when you go
up to bat with like a weighted bat and
then you use like a normal bat. And a
normal bat is the data centers that are
terrestrial. And those will probably be
used for training. When we think about
training, where latency matters. Those
are probably used for training. The
satellite layer where there is like
downlink latency happening, that's
probably more for inference where
latency matters a little bit less. But
we're going to start to see this
Starlink constellation launch as soon as
next year. With Starlink version 3 being
launched as soon as the next Starship.
So the plan for the next Starship launch
is to follow up what they did with the
previous launch, which was get these
Starlink B3 satellites into orbit. Um
now they're actually going to deploy
them, put them in orbit, turn them on,
make them work. And that takes us to the
the Starlink part of the engine, which
is pretty unbelievable as well. The
growth curve of the service is the about
as pure of an exponential curve as you
can get. They doubled their subscribers
year over year. They are now at 12
million. They just added 1.7 of those 12
million this quarter alone. So it is
just a vertical hockey stick. And I
think this is one of the more underrated
parts of the earnings report.
Uh Gwynne Shotwell, she had a lot or a
little bit to say on this as it relates
to the
ability to deploy a network similar to a
Verizon or AT&T. I mean, currently
there's on Earth there's about 5.5
billion users of the internet. Um so
they are talking about being the
pipeline for a large majority of that
and totally removing dead zones and
making it direct to cell. And the
Starlink mobile play I think is really
interesting. I remember last year we
recorded an episode where they bought a
fixed amount of spectrum to start
deploying. Once they have, their plan
seems to be that they are going to
continue to buy these dedicated pieces
of spectrum until they own enough
bandwidth to truly compete and then they
have these ground base stations which
are able to kind of handle a lot of the
bandwidth and work in higher density
areas. And when Shotwell, all she said
on the call is that they have a
foundational competitive advantage and
won't really go into the like it's just
secrets and strategies that they're
going to go with but what I expect is
that this time next year on our iPhones
we will have like pretty high
bandwidth internet connectivity. And for
that to happen that quickly seems like a
very bullish thing to me and it's just
like who wouldn't sign up for a service
that has good internet anywhere in the
world with no dead zones. I just went to
national parks last two weeks. I had no
service at all. The only thing
connecting me was Starlink terminals
here and
there but direct to cell would be such
an awesome thing and the business is
growing so quickly.
>> For context here, I couldn't reach Josh
for like 6 to 12 hours at a time. It was
absolutely insane.
>> I was in the jungle surrounded by
>> coyotes and redwoods. I I thought he'd,
you know, suffered some kind of fatal
injury or something like that. I was I I
was I What was that movie? The The 100
hours or whatever where the What was it?
Just where he gets lost out there. I was
like, damn, is is Josh okay?
>> Listen, on the on the Starlink side of
things, I think the thesis, put very
simply, is
in a world where you have these AI
models, these AI agents running 24/7 on
GPUs getting work done, you need
reliability and reliability sits in the
modern day world on the internet. Now,
you can't have lines going down. You
can't have connectivity issues. You
can't have T-Mobile messing up some of
their lines. What are some of the most
consistent ways of beaming internet
down? Well, you can do it via
satellites, right? And I would love to
have consistency with my provider as
well. Like, to be honest, like if if I
could have an affordable Starlink
connection right now on my phone mobile
package, I would move to that because
then I could just use it on the plane or
whatever that might be. So, I don't
think that this is just a temporary
trend. I think this is something similar
to AI where everyone's just going to
want consistent, strong, fast access to
the internet, and Sonic is a very
obvious win. And and and it goes back to
my earlier point, which is
Elon has his hands in a lot of different
things, and they're actually working.
They're working well individually, but
they're working well together as well.
And we're going to see that in future
quarterly earnings report.
>> All right, EJ, as you mentioned agents,
and speaking of agents, we have to talk
about a sponsor of the show, Ledger,
because if you are building with AI
agents, and you're worried about
security, which a lot of people should
be. I mean, we've had um a lot of AI
models recently that have broken out of
their sandboxes. It's a little scary. An
agent with untracked access is very
scary. So, Ledger has this three-step
process to solve this, in which an agent
proposes, a human approves, and then a
Ledger signer enforces. This technology
works with cloud code, codex, cursor,
all of the things that we are used to
using, and it's also open source to be
fully audited. Basically, they use this
thing called a Ledger agent stack, which
has a series of four open source tools.
There's a wallet, there's an enterprise
solution, there's a multi-sig, so that
you don't get compromised for any of
your transactions, and you could
basically just talk to it normally. You
could say, "Rebalance my wallet," and
it'll do all of the math and do the
transactions on your side, while letting
you approve and be in the loop the
entire time. So, just want to shout out
Ledger for a responsible way of building
with AI agents. Uh thank you so much.
You can find the link in the description
down below.
>> So, before we wrap up this episode,
Josh, I
we need to talk about the the bad case
of all of this going on. Now, we
mentioned this on a previous episode,
there is a very constricted supply of
SpaceX stock that is available for
people to currently trade. And the
number one bit of critique is it's going
to flood the gates tomorrow. Actually,
as you're listening to this episode, it
should be today on the on the 6th, $100
billion worth of SpaceX shares goes
live. And the big question on everyone's
mind is, "Where's the buying power
coming for this?" Because to keep the
price at its current level, you need
someone that is buying all of those
shares, right? And what we've seen, and
maybe this is reflected in the stock
action today, is people don't believe
that that will be the case. Now, whether
they're thinking over a short-term
period of time, whether they're thinking
of a long-term period of time, is
another question. If you're common
listeners of this show, you will know
that Josh and I think on pretty mid- to
long-term time horizons, so we're kind
of bullish in SpaceX over the long term.
Over the short term, we kind of like
don't care too much. We want to kind of
like see it as an opportunity to access
it, but nevertheless, it is a concern or
worry.
>> Yeah, no, I understand why people are
concerned and worried. And in fact, I
remember viscerally feeling this with
the Tesla story. Because Tesla, as a lot
of people don't know, was the most
shorted company in the stock exchange
for two or three years. Like everyone
was just pounding on it. It was just the
the most diabolical company ever. Like
no one was going to It was never going
to work. And now I haven't driven a car
in like a couple years. And these like
seemingly sci-fi impossible things that
are sold, a lot of people are uncertain
of their ability to happen. And that's
like totally fair. There's the key man
risk in the sense that like there is a
singular person at the helm who's in
charge of driving all this value. That
is a serious risk. There is the risk on
timelines. Often times these timelines
are very optimistic. Is there actually
going to be 15 gigawatts of compute
deployed by 2030?
If there's not, what does the revenue
look like? But even if these things are
fractionally wrong, the trajectory of
this company is one way. And when I
think about other companies, it's like
as a person who has like cash, if you
have any cash sitting in a bank account,
you have a problem because that cash
needs to earn money, otherwise you're
going to get outpaced by inflation. And
when you think of the places to deploy
that cash where the upside is the
greatest and most exciting and most
aligned with like an optimistic vision
of the future, it's hard to find
something more interesting and exciting
and mispriced
than something like SpaceX is. And it's
not like things aren't working. Like we
are seeing progress. The Starship
launches you can go and watch. You could
literally go to Texas and sit on the
highway and watch them in person. And
they get better every time. And the the
the heat shield, which is the biggest
part of reusability, finally works for
the first time ever with the last
Starship launch. And soon they're going
to land both parts of the rocket. And
then at the very least that means
they'll be able to deploy Starlink
version 3 satellites at scale. These
things are already built. It's just a
matter of a few more iterations to
getting there. The data centers thing,
we saw that they have a tremendous
amount of data center capability to
build these things quickly. So
they can do it. Can they build 15
gigawatts worth? We don't know. But
currently, I mean I'm looking at the
stock right now, it looks like it is
trading down at the time of recording
right now about 9% down to $115 as the
unlocks are happening today. And that
seems to me just fine. It's like, okay,
one and a half trillion dollars. That is
about I don't know, a little more than
1/10 of their expected revenue in four
years. It is very highly risky. In the
case that they can figure out how to
actually convert that into revenue and
actually deliver on these timelines.
There's no way this doesn't go
absolutely nuclear. So it's mostly a
matter of if, not when.
Or perhaps if and when. It's just like I
understand. I can understand the case
for both both people. For the bulls and
for the bears. I think just as someone
who has a very low time preference,
seeing the progress that's being made
and just very clearly mapping that out,
it seems very obvious to me that barring
any catastrophic problems,
this is just going to be a one-way
trajectory up. And sure there will be
bumps along the way. Sure maybe there
are unlocks and it sells off another 10%
for a couple more times. But the reality
is that a company five years from now
who is just continuing on this
trajectory without any of these
optimistic outlooks is worth more than
the company that they are today. And
like that's just kind of what I'm basing
all this off of.
>> There's a key man risk with all of this,
which is
can Elon focus all of his attention to
actually be able to pull this off? Does
he have the chops to basically execute
on the vision that he's kind of like
laid out on his earnings call? That's
that's pretty much the main thing that
you have to kind of like believe in. The
other thing is on the point of like you
know, low time horizon,
I think that you can equally be very
bullish SpaceX over the long term and be
bearish over the short term. And that
could be an opportunity for you. It just
depends on like how you want to frame
it, right? Like for example, you might
want to wait and see how the share
unlocks happen over the next couple of
months. I think something like 25 to 36%
of the entire share supply gets unlocked
in that period of time. Maybe you'll I
expect to see a lot of volatility during
that time and maybe that's like the time
for you to kind of like load up. To to
your point earlier, Josh, like Tesla was
one of the most shorted stocks ever and
it was that case for two to three years.
And maybe we'll see a similar profile
for SpaceX. You know, these valuations
are huge. Society is very unaware or
uncomfortable with these large numbers
and you know, we saw the same transition
when we saw the first hundred billion
dollar company, right? So
Meta went through this, Uber privately
went through this as well. And so we're
probably going to see the same
on SpaceX in particular. But I agree
with the trajectory in general. I think
these companies are going to do very
well. SpaceX has a very bright future
ahead of it. And to be honest, in terms
of like where the risk curve is, it is
on the furthest end out there. Like Elon
could be doing this with just one
company, but he's doing this with like
four or five combined into one. And now
there's like rumors that like they might
merge with Tesla. They might become a
whole kind of like mega corp type
situation. So if that plays out, there's
going to be even more scrutiny that's
going to be placed on him. But overall,
I think I am very bullish long term, but
maybe over the short term, I'm going to
say that I'm tentative. I'm sitting
there
with my cash and seeing whether there is
a better time to deploy and we'll see
over the next couple of weeks.
>> Yeah, you just maybe don't want to miss
the repricing. I'm looking at that Tesla
chart um between 2020 and 2021 and how
the stock 13x'd over the course of a
year as it ripped in like the largest
short squeeze ever. If you go to the
all-time chart, that 2020 to 2021 is a
pretty violent repricing and that's just
the world coming to grips with the fact
that the technology and the thesis
actually played out. In the case that
that does happen again, that's the
expectation, but there's lots of reasons
to be bearish. I mean, just today for
reference, uh there's 911 million shares
unlocking. That's a $100 billion of
potential sell-side pressure. They
guided for 39% higher CapEx this year
with no guidance given for next year,
which is interesting. They didn't guide
to where CapEx is, so that's a huge
unknown. There's the like average
revenue per user compression on the
Starlink side where Starlink revenue per
user fell 22% as they doubled
year-over-year because they're trying to
move into cheaper international markets.
So, even though the subscribers are
doubling, their revenue per user is
decreasing. So, there's a lot of these
definitely things to look out for, but
on the upside, I think of like moats and
competition,
Peter Thiel's the big monopoly guy. They
have a monopoly on so many different
industries. Even if one of them works,
this is a remarkable outcome for a one
and a half trillion-dollar company. So,
that's
>> Great.
>> That's I think it. That's the uh this
SpaceX update. That's the earnings
report. I don't know. Trying to be a
little sober about how we view this, but
like goddamn, there's no company in the
world that's more exciting than this
one.
>> [laughter]
>> Yeah.
>> It's so sick. Like okay, sure, the
master drivers on the moon, like that's
a long shot. That's going to be like
I'll be excited to live through that and
hopefully see that one day. But today,
today, Starlink, incredible. Starship,
incredible. Their ability to deploy data
centers at scale and break even after
just 12 months, incredible. There's no
one else that can manufacture at this
scale. So, just in terms of
manufacturing monopolies, it seems to me
like there's China and then there is
Tesla and SpaceX. And that's kind of the
people who are most able to move the
amount of atoms in a coherent way that
generates value and that is worth a lot.
So, yeah, I think that's everything.
That's the SpaceX update. This one
pretty long. If you listen to this, I If
you made it this far, like please let us
know how crazy this sounds to you. Like
is this is this a little too far over
index on one side or is this please
yeah, let's let's hear either way.
What's the strategy around SpaceX? How
we thinking about this 1.5 trillion
dollar company? Cuz listen, we're going
to come back here.
Couple years on the show and we're going
to reference this episode and be like
told you so or maybe not. Maybe we'll be
poor and maybe Starship will have blown
up and the show wouldn't exist. But you
know what? We just wouldn't have a
camera in front of us. Yeah, yeah, I'd
have to point off my camera. So that
maybe the worst case scenario. But yeah,
that's that's the episode. Thank you so
much for watching. You just any final
parting thoughts before we let everyone
go. Yeah, no. If you are listening to us
and you aren't subscribed to us, please
please do it. Helps us out massively
whether you're on Apple Music or
Spotify. We're on our way to 100k. We're
on our way to about to hit 70, I think
subscribers on YouTube, which is
exciting. We have a bunch of subscribers
on all the other platforms. So like
Awesome. Thank you for the support. So
cool. Welcome to all of you. I think we
added like 2,000 subscribers over the
last 28 days. Hello, it's lovely to meet
you.
We are putting out shows and episodes
about four times a week, but we also
have a newsletter that goes out to over
100,000 people. We post twice. One is a
long-form essay
and the other is kind of like the weekly
recap. But as I was saying earlier,
wherever you listen to us, leave us a
comment. Give us feedback. We're also on
X. DM us if you have thoughts, if you
disagree with us, we'd love to hear from
you even more. Give [music] us a like,
thumbs up. It helps us out massively and
yeah, I guess that's it. We'll see you
on the next
>> [music]